[
    {
        "question": "How much fund has been approved by the High-level Committee of the National Disaster Mitigation Fund for the state governments for disaster mitigation projects?",
        "options": [
            "Rs.1581.34 crore ",
            "Rs. 2556.45 crore ",
            "Rs. 2078.23 crore ",
            "Rs. 3027.86 crore "
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 3027.86 crore ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following is correct about 'Pinaka'?",
        "options": [
            "It is a multi-barrel rocket system ",
            "It is a type of battle tank ",
            "It is an advanced submarine ",
            "It is an indigenously developed drone system  "
        ],
        "answer": "It is a multi-barrel rocket system ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been roped as the brand ambassador of KRBL Ltd for its 'India Gate' brand of basmati rice?",
        "options": [
            "Hrithik Roshan ",
            "Ranveer Singh ",
            "Salman Khan ",
            "Amitabh Bachchan "
        ],
        "answer": "Amitabh Bachchan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the PM Surya Ghar Scheme:  1.It aims to boost solar rooftop capacity and enable residential households to generate their own electricity.  2.The scheme aims to help India meet its climate commitments by achieving 100% renewable energy dependency by 2040.  Which of the statement(s) given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has become first state to introduce E-Way Bill (EWB) for transportation of gold?",
        "options": [
            "for transportation of gold? ",
            "Kerala  ",
            "Maharashtra  ",
            "Gujarat  ",
            "Madhya Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "for transportation of gold? ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has appointed as the first Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of Vedanta Resources Ltd (VRL)?",
        "options": [
            "Deshnee Naidoo ",
            "Safra Catz ",
            "Carol Tom\u00e9 ",
            "Jane Fraser "
        ],
        "answer": "Deshnee Naidoo ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Mutual Fund has launched India\u2019s first MSCI India Index ETF?",
        "options": [
            "Aditya Birla Sun Life Asset Management ",
            "UTI Asset Management ",
            "SBI Mutual Fund ",
            "Kotak Mutual Fund "
        ],
        "answer": "Kotak Mutual Fund ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state was the International Saraswati Mahotsav 2025 held?",
        "options": [
            "Uttar Pradesh  ",
            "Haryana  ",
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Odisha "
        ],
        "answer": "Haryana  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company is partnering with SBI Payments to enhance digital commerce in India?",
        "options": [
            "Paytm ",
            "PhonePe ",
            "Razorpay ",
            "Pine Labs "
        ],
        "answer": "Pine Labs ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fintech firm Finvasia in collaboration with which bank has launched Jumpp Super App for Digital Finance?",
        "options": [
            "Yes Bank  ",
            "HDFC Bank  ",
            "Axis Bank  ",
            "ICICI Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Yes Bank  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "IRDAI has introduced a new regulation that caps annual premium increases for senior citizens\u2019 health insurance policies by a maximum of __.",
        "options": [
            "10% ",
            "15% ",
            "12% ",
            "20% "
        ],
        "answer": "10% ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding Point Nemo, recently seen in the news:  1. It is the deepest point on Earth.  2. It is located in the Pacific Ocean.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "2 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Axiom-4 Mission (Ax-4), recently seen in the news?",
        "options": [
            "A scientific mission to study asteroid impacts on Earth. ",
            "A commercial space mission sending astronauts to the Moon. ",
            "A mission to send a crew to Mars for the first time.  ",
            "A private astronaut mission to the International Space Station "
        ],
        "answer": "A private astronaut mission to the International Space Station ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding e-Shram microsite:  1. It is a state-specific digital platforms seamlessly integrated with the national e-Shram database.  2. It is launched by the Union Ministry of Labour & Employment.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?  Follow us: Official Site, Telegram, Facebook, Instagram, Youtube 471",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding Household Consumption Expenditure Survey:  1. It is designed to collect information on consumption and expenditure of the households on goods and services.  2. It is published by the Union Ministry of Finance every year.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the head of the Judicial Commission set up by the Uttar Pradesh government to inquire into the stampede during the Maha Kumbh in Prayagraj in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Justice Dipak Misra ",
            "Justice Harsh Kumar  ",
            "Justice Sanjiv Khanna ",
            "Justice Mehr Chand Mahajan "
        ],
        "answer": "Justice Harsh Kumar  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "After how many years is the Maha Kumbh held in India?",
        "options": [
            "120 years ",
            "130 years ",
            "111 years ",
            "144 years "
        ],
        "answer": "144 years ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Chairman of the Group of Ministers to address issues related to the viability of the electricity distribution utilities in the country?",
        "options": [
            "Hardeep Singh Puri ",
            "Jayant Chaudhary ",
            "Shripad Yesso Naik ",
            "Rao Inderjit Singh "
        ],
        "answer": "Shripad Yesso Naik ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state has approved the Sadhbhawana Legacy Cases Resolution Scheme 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Himachal Pradesh ",
            "Uttarakhand ",
            "Punjab ",
            "Rajasthan "
        ],
        "answer": "Himachal Pradesh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state government has launched WhatsApp Governance titled \u2018Mana Mitra\u2019?",
        "options": [
            "Andhra Pradesh ",
            "Uttar Pradesh  ",
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Uttarakhand "
        ],
        "answer": "Andhra Pradesh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Finance minister Nirmala Sitharaman is likely to announce the launch of  a Rs_ fund by Nabventures, a subsidiary of Nabard, for the benefit of startups in agriculture and allied sectors.",
        "options": [
            "Rs 1,000 crore ",
            "Rs 2,000 crore ",
            "Rs 3,000 crore ",
            "Rs 5,000 crore "
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 1,000 crore ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which university is set to become the first UK university to open a campus in Gujarat International Finance Tec-City (GIFT City)?",
        "options": [
            "Queen's University Belfast ",
            "Wollongong university ",
            "Deakin university ",
            "University of Bristol "
        ],
        "answer": "Queen's University Belfast ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mumbai Indians owners are set to acquire what percent stake in Hundred franchise Oval Invincibles?",
        "options": [
            "49% ",
            "33% ",
            "21% ",
            "51% "
        ],
        "answer": "49% ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state has approved the Sadhbhawana Legacy Cases Resolution Scheme 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Himachal Pradesh ",
            "Uttarakhand ",
            "Punjab ",
            "Rajasthan "
        ],
        "answer": "Himachal Pradesh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been re-appointed as the Managing Director and CEO of Maruti Suzuki?",
        "options": [
            "Kenichi Ayukawa ",
            "Maheswar Sahu ",
            "Hisashi Takeuchi ",
            "Osamu Suzuki "
        ],
        "answer": "Hisashi Takeuchi ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state has signed a 25-year power purchase agreement with Damodar Valley Corporation for 800 MW?",
        "options": [
            "Punjab ",
            "Rajasthan ",
            "Uttar Pradesh ",
            "Haryana "
        ],
        "answer": "Haryana ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Director General of the Bureau of Civil Aviation Security (BCAS)?",
        "options": [
            "Alok Verma ",
            "Rakesh Asthana ",
            "Rajesh Nirwan ",
            "Subodh Kumar Jaiswal "
        ],
        "answer": "Rajesh Nirwan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who unfurls the National Flag at the Republic Day celebration in New Delhi?",
        "options": [
            "Prime Minister  ",
            "President  ",
            "Chief Justice of India  ",
            "Ministry of Defence "
        ],
        "answer": "President  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country\u2019s armed forces contingent participated in the 76th Republic Day celebration 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Bangladesh  ",
            "Indonesia  ",
            "Japan  ",
            "Russia "
        ],
        "answer": "Indonesia  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ministry of the government of India organises \u2018Bharat Parv\u2019 festival at the Red Fort in New Delhi on the occasion of the Republic Day?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of External Affairs ",
            "Ministry of Defence ",
            "Ministry of Education ",
            "Ministry of Tourism "
        ],
        "answer": "Ministry of Tourism ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state was the International Saraswati Mahotsav 2025 held?",
        "options": [
            "Uttar Pradesh  ",
            "Haryana  ",
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Odisha "
        ],
        "answer": "Haryana  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the 10th Sci-FI Science Film Festival of India held?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai  ",
            "Panaji ",
            "New Delhi  ",
            "Chennai "
        ],
        "answer": "Panaji ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was honoured with the Asian Cinema Culture Award at the 21st Third Eye Asian Film Festival 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Javed Akhtar ",
            "Aditya Chopra ",
            "Anurag Kashyap ",
            "Salim Khan "
        ],
        "answer": "Javed Akhtar ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company is partnering with SBI Payments to enhance digital commerce in India?",
        "options": [
            "Paytm ",
            "PhonePe ",
            "Razorpay ",
            "Pine Labs "
        ],
        "answer": "Pine Labs ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]